Guide to the Jody Jones Hunter Collection of Works by William Styron, 1831-2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jody Jones Hunter Collection of Works by William Styron, 1831-2001
Hunter, Jody Jones
19.5 linear feet Extent: 645 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00591
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Jody Jones Hunter Collection of Works by William Styron was received as a gift by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1998, 2001 and 2008.
Biographical Note
Hunter is a collector of works by certain southern authors taught by William Blackburn. William Styron is an award-winning author of American literature, including such works as Sophie's Choice and The Confessions of Nat Turner. Both are Duke University alumni.
Collection Overview
The Jody Jones Hunter Collection of Works by William Styron includes first editions, limited editions, translations, and other editions, many of them autographed or inscribed, of the works of William Styron, along with published articles, correspondence, manuscripts, and related materials. The correspondence is chiefly letters written by Styron to Stuart Wright, the owner of Palaemon Press in Winston-Salem, N.C. and publisher of several limited editions of Styron's work. Also included with the collection is a carbon typescript of Confessions of Nat Turner, with holograph notes, and the original typescript of Styron's recipe for southern fried chicken from The Artist's and Writer's Cookbook (1961).
The addition (Accession 2001-0056) consists largely of books (mostly first editions, some signed or inscribed) and printed material written by or about Styron, or containing his contributions (1951-2001). Also includes editions of All the Finest Girls (2001), by Alexandra Styron (his youngest daughter); an original manuscript review of Sophie's Choice (1979) by Julian Symons; an original publisher's advertisement for The Confessions of Nat Turner (1967); an uncorrected proof of Admiral Robert Penn Warren and the Snows of Winter: A Tribute (1978?); and an original holograph manuscript of Styron's 1977 review of Philip Caputo's A Rumor of War (1977).
Addition (08-081)(5 items, .1 lin. ft.; undated) comprises a signed black-and-white photograph, and four pages of Styron's writing (two sheets are signed).
Addition (08-325)(4 items, .3 lin. ft.; dated 1982-1995 and undated) comprises two items of correspondence, a signed photograph, and an undated screenplay, SET THIS HOUSE ON FIRE.
Subject Headings
Styron, William, 1925-; Hunter, Jody Jones; Wright, Stuart T.; American literature -- 20th century; American literature -- Southern States; Authors, American -- Southern States; Authors, American -- 20th century; Literature -- History and criticism; Southampton Insurrection, 1831 -- Literature and the insurrection
Contents of Collection
- Accession (1998-0553)
  - Lie Down in Darkness
    First editions, translations, and other editions, many signed and inscribed, of Styron's first novel.
    - Lie Down in Darkness, by William Styron, Bobbs Merrill, 1951. (Box 1)
      1st edition, presentation copy.
    - Lie Down in Darkness, by William Styron, Bobbs Merrill, 1951 (Box 1)
      1st edition - Tipped in Letter - no dust jacket.
    - Lie Down in Darkness, by William Styron, Bobbs Merrill, 1951 (Box 1)
      1st edition, signed.
    - Lie Down in Darkness (uncorrected proof), by William Styron, Random House, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Lie Down in Darkness (uncorrected proof), by William Styron, Random House, 1979 (Box 1)
      Slipcased.
    - Lie Down in Darkness, by William Styron, Vintage International, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Lie Down in Darkness, by William Styron, Picador, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Un Lit De Tenebres, by William Styron, Gallimard, 1963 (Box 1)
      French edition.
    - Un Lit De Tenebres, by William Styron, Gallimard,1986 (Box 1)
    - William Styron's Lie Down in Darkness: A Screenplay, by Richard Yates, 1985 (Box 1)
      Signed by Styron and Yates.
    - William Styron's Lie Down in Darkness: A Screenplay, by Richard Yates, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Inheritance of the Night: Early Drafts of 'Lie Down in Darkness,' Duke University, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Inheritance of the Night: Early Drafts of 'Lie Down in Darkness,' William Styron and James L.W. West III, Duke University, 1993 (Box 1)
      Slipcased - letter 'J' of 26 lettered copies.
    - Inheritance of the Night: Early Drafts of 'Lie Down in Darkness,' William Styron and James L.W. West III, Duke University, 1993 (Box 1)
      #3 of 250 copies signed by Styron.
    - Inheritance of the Night: Early Drafts of 'Lie Down in Darkness,' William Styron and James L.W. West III, Duke University, 1993 (Box 1)
      Trade edition.
    - The Landscape in Nightmare: Studies in the Contemporary Novel, by Jonathon Baumbach, 1965 (Box 1)
  - The Long March (Box 1)
    First editions, first published versions, translations, and other editions of Styron's novella.
    - Discovery, No. 1, 1953 (Box 1)
      Signed by Styron; "The Long March" on page 221.
    - Discovery, No. 1, 1953 (Box 1)
      "The Long March" on page 221.
    - The Long March, Modern Library, 1956 (Box 1)
      Signed.
    - The Long March, Modern Library, 1956 (Box 1)
    - The Long March, Vintage, ca. 1964 (Box 1)
    - The Long March, Random House, 1968 (Box 1)
    - The Long March, Hamish Hamilton, 1962 (Box 1)
      British edition.
    - The Long March, Signet, 1968 (Box 1)
    - The Long March and In the Clap Shack, Plume, 1975 (Box 1)
    - The Long March, Black Swan, 1967 (Box 1)
    - The Long March and In the Clap Shack, Vintage International, 1993 (Box 1)
    - The Long March, Picador, 1994 (Box 1)
    - La Marche de Nuit, Gallimard, 1963 (Box 1)
      Pages uncut.
    - La Marche de Nuit, Gallimard, 1963 (Box 1)
    - La Marche de Nuit, Gallimard, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Den Langa Marchen, Wahlsrtom and Widstrand, 1963 (Box 1)
      Swedish edition.
  - Set This House on Fire (Box 2)
    - Set This House on Fire, Random House, 1960 (Box 2)
      1st edition, trial dust jacket.
    - Set This House on Fire, Random House, 1960 (Box 2)
    - Set This House on Fire, Random House, 1960 (Box 2)
    - Set This House on Fire, Hamish Hamilton, 1961 (Box 2)
      1st British edition, signed.
    - Set This House on Fire, Hamish Hamilton, 1961 (Box 2)
      1st British edition.
    - Set This House on Fire, Vintage International, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Set This House on Fire, Picador, 1993 (Box 2)
    - A Roman Collection: Stories, Poems, and Other Good Pieces by the Writing Residents of The American Academy in Rome, edited by Miller Williams, 1980. (Box 2)
      Excerpt from Set This House on Fire.
    - La Proie des Flammes, Gallimard, 1986-1988(2 volumes) (Box 2)
      French paperback edition.
    - Esta Casa en Llamas, Edhasa Sudamericana, 1980 (Box 2)
      Reprint of 1961spanish language edition.
    - Que o Fogo Consuma Esta Casa, Publicacoes Dom Quixote, 1988. (Box 2)
  - The Confessions of Nat Turner (Box 2)
    First editions, translations, and other editions of Styron's Pulitzer Prize-winning novel. Also includes contemporary accounts of the Turner rebellion, published excerpts of the novel, and other related publications.
    See also Box 14 (oversize).
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, Random House, 1967 (Box 2)
      1st edition; presentation copy to James Jones and his wife Gloria.
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, Random House, 1967 (Box 2)
      #23 of 500, signed, slipcased.
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, Random House, 1967 (Box 2)
      Signed on tipped in leaf.
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, Random House, 1967 (Box 2)
      Fourth printing, signed.
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, (uncorrected proof) Jonathan Cape, 1968 (Box 2)
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, Jonathan Cape, 1968 (Box 2)
      1st British edition, with Pulitzer Prize wrap.
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, Jonathan Cape, 1968 (Box 2)
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, [ Random House] 1967 (Box 2)
      Pirated edition, photo offset from the Random House edition, signed.
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, [ Random House] 1967 (Box 2)
      Pirated edition, photo offset from the Random House edition.
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, Modern Library, 1970 (Box 2)
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, Vintage International, 1993 (Box 2)
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, Modern Library, 1994 (Box 2)
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, Franklin Library, 1979 (Box 3)
      Brown leather.
    - Les Confessions de Nat Turner, Gallimard, 1969 (Box 3)
      #18 of 45 deluxe copies of 1st French edition.
    - Les Confessions de Nat Turner, Gallimard, Collection Soliel, 1969 (Box 3)
      2nd French edition.
    - Les Confessions de Nat Turner, Gallimard, 1988 (Box 3)
    - As Confissoes de Nat Turner, Rocco, 1985 (Box 3)
      Portuguese edition.
    - The Literature of the American South: A Norton Anthology, Norton, 1998 (Box 3)
    - Oxford Book of the American South, edited by Edward L Ayers, Oxford, 1997 (Box 3)
    - William Styron's Nat Turner: Ten Black Writer's Respond, edited by John Henrik Clarke, Beacon Press, 1968 (Box 3)
      1st edition.
    - William Styron's Nat Turner: Ten Black Writer's Respond, edited by John Henrik Clarke, Beacon Press, 1968 (Box 3)
    - An Illustrated History of Black Americans, by John Hope Franklin, Time-Life Books, 1973. (Box 3)
    - Vintage Reading Notebook, Winter 1993, Vintage, 1992 (Box 3)
      Text of Styron's essay "Nat Turner Revisited."
    - Dred: A Tale of the Great Dismal Swamp, by Harriet Beecher Stowe, 1856,(2 volumes) (Box 3)
    - The Southampton Insurrection, by William Sidney Drewry, 1900 (Box 3)
    - Nat Turner: Authentic and Impartial Narrative of the Tragical Scene Which Was Witnessed in Southampton County.., Warner and West, 1831, Oct. 21 (Box 3)
      1st edition. An account of the Turner uprising published nine days before his capture.
    - Southampton and Charleston Slave Insurrections, by Henry Bibb, 1849 (Box 3)
    - Great Gittin' Up Morning: A Biography of Denmark Vesey, by John Oliver Killens, 1972 (Box 3)
    - The Longest Memory, by Fred D'Aguiar, 1994 (Box 3)
    - Six Plays for the Negro Theater, by Randolph Edmonds, 1934 (Box 3)
    - Frederick Douglass, by William S. McFeely, 1991 (Box 3)
    - The Militant South, by John Hope Franklin, Harvard University Press, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Nat Turner's Slave Rebellion: The Environment, The Event, The Effects, by Herbert Aptheker, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Nat Turner's Slave Insurrection, by F. Roy Johnson, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Slave Testimony: Two Centuries of Letters, Speeches, Interviews, and Autobiographies, by John W. Blassingame, 1995 (Box 3)
    - Slavery Agitation in Virginia, 1829-1932, by Theodore M. Whitfield, Johns Hopkins Press, 1930 (Box 3)
    - From Rebellion to Revolution, by Eugene D. Genovese, 1994 (Box 3)
    - Paris Review, 36, Winter 1966 (Box 3)
      Confessions of Nat Turner excerpted.
    - Partisan Review, Vol. XXV, No. 3, Summer 1968 (Box 3)
      Responses to Nat Turner.
    - The Southern Literary Journal, Vol. II, No. 2, Spring 1970 (Box 3)
      Essay on Nat Turner by George Core.
    - Confessions of Nat Turner, by Alfred Celestine, The Many Press, 1978 (Box 3)
      Poems inspired by Nat Turner.
    - South Atlantic Quarterly, Vol. 70, No. 1, Winter 1980 (Box 3)
      Essay on Nat Turner by William McGill.
    - Harpers's Magazine, Vol. 235, No. 1408, September 1967 (Box 3)
      Lengthy excerpt of Nat Turner.
  - In the Clap Shack (Box 4)
    - In the Clap Shack,(uncorrected proof) Random House, 1973 (Box 4)
    - In the Clap Shack, Random House, 1973 (Box 4)
    - In the Clap Shack, Random House, 1973 (Box 4)
    - In the Clap Shack and The Long March, Plume, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Sophie's Choice (Box 4)
    First editions, translations, and other editions of Styron's novel. Also includes published excerpts and related materials.
    - Sophie's Choice, Franklin Library, 1979 (Box 4)
    - Sophie's Choice, (uncorrected proof), Random House, 1979 (Box 4)
    - Sophie's Choice, Random House, 1979 (Box 4)
      Advance presentation edition.
    - Sophie's Choice, Random House, 1979 (Box 4)
      Slipcased, signed limited edition, #490 of 500.
    - Sophie's Choice, Random House, 1979 (Box 4)
      1st trade edition.
    - Sophie's Choice, (Uncorrected proof), Jonathan Cape, 1979 (Box 4)
    - Sophie's Choice, Jonathan Cape, 1979 (Box 4)
    - Le Choix de Sophie, Gallimard, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Sophie's Choice, Vintage International, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Sophie's Choice, Picador, 1993 (Box 4)
    - La Proie des Flammes / Le Choix de Sophie, Gallimard Biblos, 1989 (Box 4)
    - Le Choix de Sophie, Gallimard, 1989-90 (Box 4)
      Two volumes.
    - Sofien Valinta, Kunstannusokeyhtio Otavo, 1983 (Box 4)
      1st Finnish Edition.
    - Sophie's Val, Whalstrom and Widstrand, 1984 (Box 4)
    - Sophie's Choice, Corgi, 1987 (Box 4)
    - La Decision de Sophie, Grijalbo, ca. 1984 (Box 4)
    - Sophia, Vol. I and II, Edicao, undated (Box 5)
    - Writers on World War II: An Anthology, edited by Mordecai Richler, Knopf, 1997 (Box 5)
    - On Writers and Writing, by John Gardner, Addison Wesley, 1979 (Box 5)
      Contains review of Sophie's Choice.
    - Sewanee Review, Vol. CV, No. 3, Summer 1997 (Box 5)
      Essay on the making of the movie "Sophie's Choice."
    - The Archive, Vol. 89, No. 2, Spring 1977 (Box 5)
      Excerpt from Sophie's Choice.
    - Girlfriends: 146 Literary Heroines, Lakin and Marley Rare Books, Catalogue Four, 1995 (Box 5)
  - This Quiet Dust and Other Writings (Box 5)
    - This Quiet Dust, Random House, 1967(2 copies) (Box 5)
      Bound copy of essay used in promotion of Confessions of Nat Turner.
    - This Quiet Dust and Other Writings, (uncorrected proof), Random House, 1982 (Box 5)
    - This Quiet Dust and Other Writings, Random House, 1982 (Box 5)
      1st edition, # 73 of 250, signed, slipcased.
    - This Quiet Dust and Other Writings, Random House, 1982(2 copies) (Box 5)
    - This Quiet Dust and Other Writings, Jonathan Cape, 1983 (Box 5)
    - This Quiet Dust and Other Writings, Vintage International, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Cette Paisible Poussiere et Autre Ecrits, Gallimard, 1985 (Box 5)
      1st French edition.
    - The South Today: 100 Years After Appomattox, edited by Willie Morris, Harper and Row, 1965 (Box 5)
    - Writers and Issues, edited by Theodore Solotaroff, Signet, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Voices in Black and White: Writings on Race in America from Harper's Magazine, edited by Katharine Whitmore, Franklin Square Press, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Voices in Black and White: Writings on Race in America from Harper's Magazine, edited by Katharine Whitmore, Franklin Square Press, 1993 (Box 5)
      1st paperback edition.
  - Darkness Visible (Box 5)
    - Darkness Visible,(uncorrected proof), Random House, 1990(2 copies) (Box 5)
    - Darkness Visible, Random House, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Darkness Visible, Random House, 1990 (Box 5)
      1st large print edition.
    - Frost and Fire: 50 Depressive and Manic Depressive Writers of Genius...A Celebration, Catalogue Three, Lakin and Marley Rare Books, Spring 1995 (Box 5)
  - A Tidewater Morning (Box 5)
    - A Tidewater Morning, Eurographica, 1990 (Box 5)
      #304 of 350 copies signed.
    - A Tidewater Morning, (uncorrected proof), Random House, 1993(2 copies) (Box 5)
    - A Tidewater Morning, Random House, 1993 (Box 5)
      1st edition, signed, #47 of 200 slipcased.
    - A Tidewater Morning, Vintage International, 1994 (Box 5)
    - A Tidewater Morning, Picador, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Limited Editions (Box 5)
    Chiefly fine press editions of Styron's writings. Some trade editions of collected works are also included. See also Box 15 (oversize).
    - The Best American Short Stories 1979, edited by Joyce Carol Oates, Houghton Mifflin, 1979 (Box 5)
      Includes "Shadrach."
    - Shadrach, Sylvester and Orphanos, 1979 (Box 5)
    - Great Esquire Fiction: The Finest Stories from the 1st Fifty Years, edited by L. Rust Hills, Penguin, 1983 (Box 5)
    - The Paris Review Anthology, edited by George Plimpton, Norton, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Christchurch, Briar Patch Press, 1977 (Box 6)
    - Admiral Robert Penn Warren and The Snows of Winter, Palaemon Press, 1978 (Box 6)
      Galley proofs, signed by Styron.
    - Admiral Robert Penn Warren and the Snows of Winter, Palaemon Press, 1978 (Box 6)
      1st edition, letter 'R" of 26 lettered copies.
    - Admiral Robert Penn Warren and the Snows of Winter, Palaemon Press, 1981 (Box 6)
      2nd edition, letter 'B' of 26 lettered copies.
    - Admiral Robert Penn Warren and the Snows of Winter, Palaemon Press, 1981 (Box 6)
      2nd edition, number viii of 50 roman numeral copies.
    - Admiral Robert Penn Warren and the Snows of Winter, Palaemon Press, 1981 (Box 6)
      2nd edition, number 39 of 100.
    - Admiral Robert Penn Warren and the Snows of Winter, Palaemon Press, 1981 (Box 6)
      2nd edition, #53 of 100.
    - Great Fiction from Esquire Fortnightly, Esquire, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Message from Auschwitz, Press de al Warr, 1979 (Box 6)
      Letter 'O' of 26 lettered.
    - Message from Auschwitz, Press de al Warr, 1979 (Box 6)
      #84 of 200 copies.
    - An Address at the 204th Commencement of Hampden-Sydney College, May 23, 1980, Hampden-Sydney College, 1980 (Box 6)
      #50 of 1000 copies.
    - Against Fear, Palaemon Press, 1981 (Box 6)
    - As He Lay Dead, A Bitter Grief, Albondocani Press, 1981 (Box 6)
      Letter 'Z' of 26 copies.
    - As He Lay Dead, A Bitter Grief, Albondocani Press, 1981 (Box 6)
      #237 of 300 copies.
    - Mr. Jefferson and Our Times, Stuart Wright, 1984 (Box 6)
      Signed, edition limited to 75 copies.
    - Letter to the Editor of the Paris Review, Press de la Warr, 1986 (Box 6)
      Letter 'L' of 26 copies.
    - Letter to the Editor of the Paris Review, Press de la Warr, 1986 (Box 6)
      #16 of 26 copies.
    - Historic Houses: Thomas Wolfe Remembered, Thomas Wolfe Memorial Historical Site, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Blankenship, Press de la Warr, 1988 (Box 6)
      #2 of 100 copies.
    - Blankenship, Press de la Warr, 1988 (Box 6)
      #14 of 100 copies.
    - A Chance in a Million, Press de al Warr, 1993(3 copies) (Box 6)
    - Grateful Words About F. Scott Fitzgerald, F. Scott Fitzgerald Society, 1997 (Box 6)
  - Books and Periodicals Containing Materials By Styron (Box 7)
    Published works containing writings by Styron, chiefly short nonfiction pieces, interviews, forwards and introductions, and cover "blurbs." For additional periodicals see also Clippings, Box 13 (oversize)
    - Writers Dreaming, edited by Naomi Epel, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Stop Time, by Frank Conroy, 1967 (Box 7)
      Blurb by Styron.
    - The Human Experience: Contemporary American and Soviet Fiction and Poetry (proof), 1989 (Box 7)
      Forward by Styron.
    - Conversations with William Styron, edited by James L. W. West III, 1985 (Box 7)
      Cloth edition.
    - Conversations with William Styron, edited by James L. W. West III, 1985 (Box 7)
      Paperback.
    - Arthur Miller and Company, edited by Christopher Bigsby, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Self-Portrait: Book People Picture Themselves, edited by Burt Britton, 1976 (Box 7)
    - To Reach Eternity: The Letters of James Jones, edited by George Hendrick, 1989 (Box 7)
    - At Random: The Reminiscences of Bennett Cerf, by Bennett Cerf, 1977 (Box 7)
    - Doing Justice: A Trial Judge at Work, by Robert Satter, 1990 (Box 7)
      Introduction by Styron.
    - Authors Take Sides on Vietnam, edited by Cecil Woolf, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Selections from the First Two Issues of the New York Review of Books, Winter/Spring 1963, edited by Robert B. Silvers, 1988 (Box 7)
    - Proceedings of the American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, Second Series, No. 41, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Proceedings of the American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, Second Series, No. 26, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Proceedings of the American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, Second Series, No. 21, 1971 (Box 7)
    - The Rushdie Letters, edited by Steve McDonogh, 1993 (Box 7)
    - One and Twenty: Duke Narrative and Verse, 924-1945, edited by William Blackburn, 1945 (Box 7)
      1st edition, signed by Styron.
    - One and Twenty: Duke Narrative and Verse, 1924-1945, edited by William Blackburn, 1945 (Box 7)
    - Under Twenty-Five: Duke Narrative and Verse, 1945-1962, edited by William Blackburn, 1963 (Box 7)
    - The Big Love, by Florence Aadland, 1986 (Box 7)
      Blurb and introduction by Styron.
    - Fighting Words: Writers Lambast other Writers, edited by James Charlton, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Writers at Work, the Paris Review Interviews, edited by Malcolm Cowley, 1958 (Box 7)
    - Writers at Work, the Paris Review Interviews, edited by Malcolm Cowley, 1959 (Box 7)
    - American Vanguard,1950, edited by Charles Glicksberg, 1950 (Box 7)
    - Best Short Stories from the Paris Review, 1959 (Box 7)
      Introduction by William Styron.
    - Writers at Work, the Paris Review Interviews: Ninth Series (uncorrected proof), edited by George Plimpton, 1992 (Box 8)
    - Writers at Work, the Paris Review Interviews: Ninth Series, edited by George Plimpton, 1992 (Box 8)
    - The Morning and The Evening, by Joan Williams, 1961 (Box 8)
    - Peter Mathiessen: A Bibliography, by D. Nicholas, 1979 (Box 8)
    - The Human Experience: Contemporary American and Soviet Fiction and Poetry, 1989 (Box 8)
    - To Reach Eternity: The Letters of James Jones, edited by George Hendrick, 1989 (Box 8)
    - Double Exposure, by Roddy McDowall, 1966 (Box 8)
    - On the Vineyard, by Peter Simon, 1980 (Box 8)
    - The Artist's and Writer's Cookbook, edited by Beryl Barr, 1961 (Box 8)
    - In the Kennedy Style, by Letticia Baldrige, 1998 (Box 8)
    - First Words: Earliest Writing from Favorite Contemporary Authors, edited by Paul Mandelbaum, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Workshop: A Spontaneous Approach to Literature, by Robert Crotty, 1971 (Box 8)
    - Means of Escape, by Philip Caputo, 1991 (Box 8)
    - William Styron: A Descriptive Bibliography, by James L.W. West III, 1977 (Box 8)
    - In Solitude and In Company: The Writings of William Styron, by James L.W. West III and Robert Byrd, 1998 (Box 8)
    - The Paris Review, 106, 1988,Spring. (Box 8)
    - Law and Disorder: The Chicago Convention and Its Aftermath, ca. 1968 (Box 8)
      Essay by Styron.
  - Books and Periodicals Containing Materials about Styron (Box 8)
    Published interviews, short biographical profiles, analysis, and photographs. Also includes two works by Styron's wife, the poet Rose Burgunder Styron.
    - Parting the Curtains, by Dannye Romine Powell, 1994 (Box 8)
    - The Absurd Hero in American Fiction, by David Galliway, 1981 (Box 8)
    - The Achievement of William Styron, edited by Robert K. Morris, 1981 (Box 8)
    - The Novels of William Styron: From Harmony to History, by Gavin Cologne-Brookes, 1995 (Box 8)
    - The Writer's Image: Literary Portraits, by Jill Krementz, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Images of the Southern Writer, by Mark Morrow, 1985 (Box 8)
    - From Summer to Summer, by Rose Burgunder Styron, 1966 (Box 9)
    - Thieves Afternoon, by Rose Burgunder Styron, 1973 (Box 9)
    - Southern Writers, by William Starr, 1997 (Box 9)